

## **IDENTITY STATEMENT**

George is a data scientist with more than nine years of product development experience in various industries (Financial Technology, Digital Media, Marketing Technology, Telecommunications). A Scrum practitioner, he advocates for an agile product development approach to data science and analytics.

## **KEY SKILLS**

- Product Development
- Project Management (Scrum)
- Data Strategy
- Data Visualization
- Data Mining
- Natural Language Processing
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Cloud Computing
- Network Science

## TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Python
- SQL
- Tableau
- Gephi
- Selenium
- Orange
- Amazon Web Services
- Apache Spark
- Microsoft Office
- Google Suite

#### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

#### AWARDS/HONORS

- Most Outstanding M.S. Graduate of the U.P. College of Science (2009)
- Most Outstanding B.S. Applied Physics Graduate, U.P. Diliman (2007)
- Magna Cum Laude, U.P. Diliman (GWA 1.262/1.000)
- U.P. Oblation Scholarship (2002)
- DOST-SEI Merit Scholarship (2002)

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Esleta, G. A., & Monterola, C. (2009). Effect of memory and reinforcement on the propagation and morphology of fracture in a two-dimensional mass-spring system. International Journal of Modern Physics C, 20(07).
- Esleta, G. A., & Monterola, C. (2008). Structural reinforcement in a spring-block model of stress-induced fracture propagation. Computer Physics Communications 178(9).

# **GEORGE ALLAN PEREZ ESLETA**

DATA SCIENCE | DATA ANALYTICS | AGILE PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT

in linkedin.com/in/gpesleta

✓ gesleta@aim.edu

T +639298874852

## **EDUCATION**

2019-Present MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DATA SCIENCE

Asian Institute of Management
Date of Graduation: June 2020

Capstone Project: Development of an Al-Enabled Lead Scoring and Cross Sell Recommender System: Targeting New Prospects and

Identifying Potential Services for Existing Clients

2007-2009 MASTER OF SCIENCE IN PHYSICS

University of the Philippines Diliman

April 2009

2002-2007 BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN APPLIED PHYSICS

University of the Philippines Diliman

April 2007

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **VOYAGER INNOVATIONS, INC.**

Senior Product Development Specialist
Responsibilities: Product Development, Data Privacy Compliance

 Led the ideation and product development of the enhanced know-your-customer (KYC) process of PayMaya. The user experience was streamlined by replacing the inapp video call with a video recording, resulting in reduced approval time and improved operational efficiency.

 Centralized monitoring of user consent and opt-ins for the Voyager Group by leading the product development and deployment of a common consent platform and

integrating it will all consumer touchpoints.

#### **VOYAGER INNOVATIONS, INC.**

2016-2017

2017-2019

#### **Senior Analytics Lead**

Responsibilities: Data Analytics, Data Strategy, Data Privacy Compliance

- Managed Voyager's data privacy compliance program and acted as the group's point
  of contact with the PLDT Group Data Privacy Council, helping Voyager achieve one of
  the highest compliance rates among PLDT and its subsidiaries.
- Consolidated the data sources of the various business units and created a single source of truth by formulating the data warehousing strategy and coordinating with IT and Engineering teams for its implementation.
- Automated the reporting requirements of the Finance department and the Management Committee by spearheading the development of management dashboards using Tableau.

#### **VOYAGER INNOVATIONS. INC.**

2014-2016

### **Product Development Lead**

Responsibilities: Product Development

- Increased the digital presence of the noontime television show Eat Bulaga! by leading the product development and successful launch of Eat Bulaga! Mobile, rated as the Top Free Entertainment application in Google Play Store for eight consecutive weeks with more than 500,000 downloads and 10,000 monthly active users.
- Provided support to TV5's coverage of the 2016 Philippine elections by leading the
  product development of the survey platform that powered the Bilang Pilipino-SWS
  mobile survey. This pioneering project tracks the opinions of a statistically
  representative panel of voters via mobile phones and provides results in 24 hours.

#### SMART COMMUNICATIONS, INC.

2010-2013

**Senior Business Analyst** 

## UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES DILIMAN

2007-2009

Instructor